Suzuki! Morning!
Oh, Azuma. Morning!
Your plushie's from that movie, isn't it?
That's right! Fluffy-chan.
Who'd you go with?
Nabe? Sato?
Well, um...
Tani-kun.
Huh? Why Tani?
We're dating.
You're what?! You didn't say anything!
I sort of forgot to!
Tell me this stuff, you moron!
Wait, how? And when?
Super recently.
How did it happen?
Um...
Who made the first move?
That would be...
Was it blackmail?
Listen to what I'm saying.
~ EXPLANATION
SCENE
OMITTED ~
Whoa, seriously? For real?
I can't tell what kind of reaction that is.
The good kind.
I'm super jealous. Just, you know, that hit
dealt some major damage. It's exhausting.
Um, thank you?
And, Suzuki, you're super composed
about it all. That surprised me.
Me? Not Tani-kun?
If you want to fall in love
with a decent person,
you yourself need a level of respectability.
Did something happen?
If only my boyfriend had been like Tani.
He suddenly stopped texting,
and I wondered if he'd ghosted me,
but the truth was that
he got thrown in juvie. Ta-da!
But it's not the kind of thing
that normally happens, right?
Awesome, right? I wish him much happiness.
Nope. That normally doesn't happen.
* JUVIE = JUVENILE DETENTION
Taira, do you watch movies and stuff?
I like movies, but audiences...
It's like a gacha pull, so I'm not a fan.
Gapacho said the same thing.
I wanna go see the one with
the witch and the fluffy guy.
You don't seem the type.
But still, you know?
Oh, that's Suzuki's voice.
I mean, I don't know, but I think
it depends on the person, right?
She's so loud.
No, really. I only ever fall in love with scum.
Whenever I get that "oh, my!"
as a first impression, the guy's always scum.
It's first thing in the morning.
What are you talking about?
We're talking about how Azu
can find herself a happy romance.
I just don't get a yummy vibe from honest men.
Yeah, I think it's too late for her.
Girls seem to like thugs, right?
Pretty girls are more likely
to date older delinquents.
What's up with that?
That's just your memories from middle school.
But, to be honest, when someone has a little
bit of bad in their aura, it's kinda cool,
SUDAKEN
and I totally understand
being attracted to them!
Suzuki, you do love your SudaKen, don't you?
So basically, in the end, you're just
choosing people based on a hierarchy.
GA
HA
The HIERARCHY
You're not looking at what's inside a person.
You're looking at their position.
You want to be someone
who's dating someone in the top group,
and you want to brag about
being with that person.
SudaKen makes my heart race!
It's so stupid.
There you go again.
Hey, Suzuki! Should you
be saying stuff like that?
Tani's here.
What?!
SLOW
Tani-kun! Good morning!
Morning.
She's an idiot.
Tani-kun, did you hear that just now?
I heard it, but I'm not going to get
worried over every little thing.
Wow. Suzuki's adorable.
I think her entertainment
factor wins out.
So do I.
Huh? What? What do they mean?
Oh.
Those two are dating.
BLABBERMOUTH
What?!
Huh? Wait, why is everyone acting normal?
They're accepting it so easily,
but the first thing they thought had to be...
"Suzuki, are you really fine with Tani?"
Because, I mean, Tani is...
OUTLIER
SUZUKI WITH FRIENDS
SudaKen makes
my heart race!
There
you
go
again.
SudaKen
makes
my
heart
race!
Nope.
Does
he
even
exist?
I want someone
who takes the lead,
someone who's
just a little forceful...
I want someone who
takes the lead...
Suzuki's ideal and her reality
are just too far apart, aren't they?
A music video
with a ton of
strong men in it
is the best, right?
Sup! Morning, Tani!
Good morning.
And how are you able to act
like you've always been friends?
Is that from the movie?
Mine's over here!
Stop wafting hints this way!
HA
WAFT?
Waft?
Oh, that's right! Suzuki, what about pictures?
W-We didn't take any!
Definitely a lie.
A photo?
Tani-kun, shh!
What? I wanna see!
Show me! Show me!
No, stop! Stay away!
Wow. For real?
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
Ugh, it's so hot.
Vending machine...
Hey! Sup, Taira!
Sup.
Sorry, if you're after a Reality
Gold Strong, I just got the last one.
I don't drink junk like that.
What? But it's so good, though.
Hey, Suzuki...
Why Tani?
Huh?
SHUDDER
"You should pick me"?
No, nothing like that. And don't shudder.
It's just, Suzuki...
YAY
Unlike happy-go-lucky types
like Yamada or Watanabe,
you're always reading the room.
You worry about what other people think, right?
BULLSEYE
That's what you think of me?
Dating someone who's that
different from you... It's unexpected.
To be honest, I've always worried about it.
Balancing with everyone around me,
wondering what people think of me...
But maybe it's because
I'm like this that the opposite...
That someone like Tani-kun, who never
wavers in who he is, looks cool to me.
Um, so...
Well...
It'd take another two hours to really
tell you about my love. Is that okay?
Spare me. The excess sugar
would make me vomit.
Sitting by the window...
is so hot.
Ta-da!
I've always wanted to do that!
Did I surprise you?
You surprised me.
Really, though?
That's that thing couples do all the time!
TOUCH
I bought drinks. Which do you want?
A Strong mini?
Why are they both Reality Golds?
This one.
Of course.
How much was it?
You don't need to pay me back!
But...
Seriously, you're so conscientious.
It pains me, but I can't help overhearing.
In that case... three yen!
It's not a grocery bag.
Don't they just get along so well?
Hey, Suzuki, you're back!
What is that?
The sports drink I froze won't melt,
so I'm going around
hitting it on harder stuff.
Please don't do stuff
like a god of destruction.
Suzuki!
What is it now?
Show me your homework!
Again? You've been asking
too much lately. Do it yourself!
Tani?
STARE
Stop it!
So, you're not gonna ask me?
I mean, I've done it, but...
They're already using him for their own ends.
It won't help you. Are you okay with that?
It would totally save me.
You nitwit! Take a hint!
Suzuki is really looking at Tani.
And everyone around her sees it
as her choice, so they don't reject it.
Give it! Give it to me!
No! Do it yourself!
None of them are worried
about other people's judgment.
Honestly! Come on!
Oh. I see.
I think I kinda get it in spite of myself.
The fact that someone who
wasn't really in my field of vision
suddenly got accepted and
acknowledged makes me feel conflicted.
And thinking that the guy must've
compromised makes things feel ludicrous.
The reason I'm so concerned
with other people's words, actions,
social standing, and rank...
is because I have no personal basis
to rate those things with.
Taira, what's wrong?
SILENCE
People who have a firm sense of self
don't waver because of changes in others.
They have their own independent identity!
I'm the one who's bound by a hierarchy.
Huh? What's that? You're scaring me.
Oh! TairAzuma, good work today!
Don't stick our vowels together.
Are you walking home together?
Yeah!
Later!
See you tomorrow!
Just look at how brazen
they are, side by side like that.
Walking home together
without a care for who sees them...
You know, somehow...
those two can make you dream, right?
Well, you did debut a new you in high school.
Shut up.
SAME MIDDLE SCHOOL
Say, Suzuki-san?
HM?
If, for example, there was a certain
ideal type of person you liked,
I do think it would be good for me
to get closer to that ideal,
but I don't think I can deviate
from my own sense of ethics and morals.
What?
ME THIS MORNING
SUDAKEN
When someone has a little bit of
bad in their aura, it's kinda cool,
and I totally understand
being attracted to them!
I knew it! You are bothered by it!
I'm not bothered.
No, if it really didn't bother you,
you wouldn't bring it up!
I'm... not bothered.
That's a lie!
Hey.
Why do you seem happy?
Well, I mean...
Sorry. I'm sorry.
Tani-kun.
There are a lot of different types
that I like. Do you understand?
Yes, I understand.
And the "that's so cool" feeling
could be because of their looks,
their inner self, or their actions.
There are a lot of different genres
of adoration, you know?
Yes. I know.
That face you're making is so adorable!
SO ADORABLE
THAT'S
BRUTAL
That's devastatingly adorable, though!
BUT IT'S
ADORABLE
After all, people...
just can't help being attracted
to their ideal sense of coolness!
ANXIETY...
Tani-kun, you're so adorable!
So adorable!
Suzuki-san, what does that mean?
Tiny Tani-kun is so adorable!
I can't breathe.
SMOOSH...
Oh. You're up early.
Tempura woke me up.
My, my. Tempura is as adorable as ever today.
ADORABLE
UNDERSTAND
DON'T UNDERSTAND
SUDAKEN
When someone has a little bit of
bad in their aura, it's kinda cool,
and I totally understand
being attracted to them!
There are a lot of different types that I like.
I said that it didn't bother me,
but Suzuki-san's idea of coolness...
is it strength?
If it is, then I...
WOBBLE
So weighty.
Oh, honestly!
Get out of the way!
Mom, where are my gym clothes?
What?
I'm not coming home tonight,
so I don't need dinner!
Stop saying everything at the same time!
Let me ride part of the way!
Crap!
Oh, hey! This far is okay!
Don't give me orders!
Thank you! Thank you!
The way Suzuki gets to school is kinda gnarly.
STARTLE
Right?
Why are you asking me?
Why's she standing so close?
DEJA VU
HEY!
Tani, do you know who
that was on the motorcycle?
No.
Suzuki!
Oh! Azuma—
MESSY
Tani-kun!
Huh? What's this? Why are you together?
Morning.
Hey, that was your older brother
just now, right?
Huh? Yeah, it was.
What?
Getting dropped off on
a motorcycle is so awesome.
Introduce me to your brother.
Azuma, I've told you, your taste is just awful.
Right, Tani-kun?
Please leave me out of the discussion.
Feel better?
GRIN
Speaking of which, Tani-kun,
do you have siblings?
I don't.
Oh, yeah, I can see that.
I wonder what they mean by "I can see that."
Suzuki, does your brother have a girlfriend?
No idea, but even if he doesn't,
I definitely cannot recommend him to you.
What on earth am I seeing?
TANI STUCK IN THE MIDDLE
AFTER SCHOOL
Right! Now we shall go home!
Suzuki-san.
Huh?
I'm the library assistant today,
so I'll be staying.
Oh, really?
Well, we have to accept
what's beyond our control.
GLOOM
She doesn't seem like she accepts it.
LIBRARY
SNEAK
Huh?
Suzuki-san?
STARTLE
Is something wrong?
Oh, um, well...
When I thought about it, I realized
that I've never really used the library,
so I thought I'd take this opportunity
to come and take a look, you know?
Sorry! I'm being kinda stalker-y, right?
I would never think that.
Really? That's a relief.
Actually, if I had to choose,
I'd say I was happy.
Oh! Should I have told her that?
But I don't want to make her
wait here for too long.
Suzuki-san.
If you get bored, you can leave first.
FWISH...
I mean, we are talking about me here,
but I can read, you know?
No, that isn't what I meant.
CAUGHT
THE
HINT
GASP
Actually, forget what I just said!
Maybe I'll just borrow a book
and head home for today.
He's right. It's annoying having someone
just hanging around for no reason.
SUZUKI IN READ-THE-ROOM MODE
FRIEND
ENERGY
Like when friends come to your part-time job
WORK
SMILE
FRIEND
ENERGY
and you don't know which version
of yourself to show them.
WORK
SMILE
FRIEND
ENERGY
WORK
SMILE
FRIEND
ENERGY
WORK
SMILE
FRIEND
ENERGY
I feel like...
she didn't take that the way I meant it.
Suzuki-san.
This place closes at five o' clock.
Can you wait?
SHINE
WORDS AND THOUGHTS
CONVERSATIONAL ABILITY = METHOD OF CONVEYANCE
COMMUNICATION
COMPETENCE
CONVERSATIONAL
ABILITY =
METHOD OF
CONVEYANCE
WORDS
AND
THOUGHTS
GASP
FWIP
Up until now...
the meaning of words beyond the literal...
SO ADORABLE
the difference between what's seen
on the surface and what lies beneath...
THAT'S
BRUTAL
BUT IT'S
ADORABLE
or, conversely, wondering if my intent
was properly conveyed through my words...
I never gave any of it a second thought.
FWISH...
Conveying thoughts through words
and comprehending
thoughts through words alone...
it's hard to do that perfectly.
Right now, I can't help worrying
over every slight gap in understanding.
RETURNING THE KEY
EXCITED
Oh, Gomapon!
Gomapon, are you headed home now, too?
Can't you tell by looking?
GOMAPON     ( GOtou MAsaru )
—
SOCIAL STUDIES
TEACHER
Hey, your bike's electric! That's hilarious!
Don't laugh. And get home
before the sun goes down.
Will do!
Suzuki-san, sorry to keep you waiting.
Gomapon just left for home.
He was on a bike.
Why wouldn't he ride a bike?
It's just the bike he was riding was so tiny!
The wheels were the size of anpan!
I couldn't help thinking he looked so adorable!
There it is again.
Suzuki-san, when you say "adorable,"
what do you mean?
Huh? What do I mean?
For example, I understand
how a cat or a panda is adorable,
but when it comes to Gotou-sensei,
I don't understand.
Oh, that's what you're asking.
How can I put it other than "adorable"?
It's like my heart gets squeezed, or...
SQUEEZE
Endearing!
Something like that, maybe?
But I guess guys don't really use
the word "adorable" all that much, huh?
Later!
I might keep going to the library!
The book I borrowed
is part of a series, after all!
I read that a long time ago, too.
Really?
Then, if I read it,
we'll be able to talk about it!
Tani-kun, tell me some books
you recommend sometime!
What? But...
I mean, our tastes
are probably totally different!
But, it's like, not everything
has to match perfectly, you know?
Like, we can get to know more
about each other, little by little...
and when one of us says, "I like this,"
the other can say, "Yeah,
seems like something you'd like."
I want to become someone
who knows things like that.
Suzuki-san.
I won't be able to become someone
that fits your idea of coolness.
But...
You're adorable.
Do you understand what I mean?
Yes...
Then... I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah...
Oh! It's Tani!
Tani! Morning!
Good morning.
Hey, Tani?
The other day, I asked Suzuki, "Why Tani?"
Huh? You asked her that?
She said that the way you know
who you are is cool.
What?
What kind of terrible reaction is that?
It's just, why would you go
out of your way to tell me that?
Huh?
Because being complimented when you
aren't around makes you the happiest, right?
BAM
Wouldn't it be better
to hear them in person?
They might be saying it in
just to make you feel better.
They'll only say what they really
think when you're not around.
You are way too suspicious of people.
Huh? Wait, does that mean
you want to make Tani happy?
You have a strange way of showing kindness.
Taira-kun...
you're a good person.
Like I said, there's no need for that!
I'm in the process of confronting
my own negative emotions,
and I just happened to do something nice
for you. I am not a good person!
Wow, you're a lot of work.
What kind of manga is it?
I told you, it's a book.
Suzuki, you reading a book is...
Huh?
That's a weird combo.
You're right.
Any longer, and I'd have had to listen
to her adoration for two hours.
Huh?
There you go making Tani happy again.
Tani-kun is smiling, right? That's unusual.
TREMBLE
Why...
I'm so jealous!
DANG IT!
I know that I'm way funnier than them!
Why are you competing there?